Let's look at some grammar now.
So the first grammar is "hurts."
"hurts"
So hurts is a verb
and here's a crab pinching the boy's nose.
He can say, "help! It hurts."
It hurts...
or you can say
"Her knee hurts."
'Her knee hurts."
So maybe you fall and you can say,
"Oh! My leg hurts."
My hand hurts.
Maybe you see your friend
and it's hard for him to hold things with his hand
you can say, what's wrong?
he says, "my hand hurts."
It hurts very much.
ah..."ache"
"ache"
"Ache" is very similar to hurts.
Ache can be a verb or a noun.
So ache is something that hurts.
So you can say,
"His head aches so much"
or "he has a headache."
or...
This ache is very severe.
So ache can be a verb or a noun.
Usually when we use "ache" as a noun.
We usually say what aches?
I have a headache.
I have a toothache
or maybe your doctor can ask you
Do you have any aches or pains?
And you can say, "Yes, doctor."
Everyday I have a headache.
My head hurts so much.
I hope that is not you.
I hope you don't have headaches everyday.
"pay"
Is to pay money.
You can pay money here.
Pay money at the store.
She pays her bill with a credit card or a card.
"pay"
"Pay can also be use to talk...
talk about visiting something.
You can say I paid the doctor a visit.
Which means I visited a doctor.
But pay, usually means to pay money.
You have to pay money.
You can't just leave with out paying for the bread.
"stop"
"Stop" is to stop moving.
So move, move, move, move, stop.
Move, stop.
So they stop for security checkpoint.
So you are driving your car, you see a stop sign
says stop.
You have to stop.
"take"
So take is to grab something
or to take something.
This first is taking a cookie.
This person is taking something from the box.
"take"
He's taking her order.
So take isn't always you have to pick something up.
So she is giving him her order.
She says, I want to eat ahh...
one bowl of soup
and he says
I can take your order.
So he will write your order.
He takes your order.
He listens to you and he takes your order
and goes and
gives it to the cook
and the cook makes your food
so that's take.
"Taking"
Can also be use for
to ride something.
I am taking the bus today.
She is taking a taxi to the store.
I am taking my bike
so
taking or take
has many uses,
to ride
or to pick something up
or
to receive something.
All are okay
for using the word take.